Hi, my name is Lena um Casten. I am the
sales lead for all of North America.
Super excited to be here today. Hey
everyone, thank you for uh inviting me
to join you all. So from a Microsoft
partner perspective as the AI
capabilities grows, what kind of impact
do you expect to see on their business
models and delivery methods and how
would you advise them to make that
transition?
I think with Microsoft partners it's
it's kind of similar, right? One of the
things is Microsoft partners have to
also become a little more technical in
the AI space because just blindly saying
we're going to do AI or we're not going
to do AI that that just doesn't work
because AI is every single product. I
think we have 150 Microsoft products
that have AI functionality in them and
that's going to be any product we
release going forward as well. And any
customuilt things partners built
themselves are probably going to have AI
in them also. So first is to get deeper
and say I'm going to really understand
what this AI thing is rather than
blindly making an API call and feeling
comfortable with that. So one is scale
yourself deeply understand AI. Second
one is go and look at those longunning
problems that your customers have had
the ones that we have not solved and
figure out what are the potential
solutions that exist that might be able
to solve those. and if not what are the
solutions that could exist and start
working closely with Microsoft start
working with yourselves other partners
ISPs to start building those solutions
because the point of AI is to accelerate
innovation that is legitly the point so
we can get through all of the things
that we've not been able to solve and
actually get to new innovation in the
space because one of the things that
I've realized is that we're still stuck
in the same admin back office stuff that
we've been doing for 25 appears and the
fact that we have not been able to
figure out how to move data from here to
there in an easier way so we can
actually do all the new fangled things.
There's a problem right there. So for
partners, you know, get more technical
um go figure out what are the problems
that customers have not been able to
solve. And third, build out your
community and network of people because
many of these solutions that we're going
to build going forward need to come from
a group of people. They're not going to
be built by a solo hero. It's going to
be some combination of partners, other
partners, ISPs and Microsoft.
>> Yeah. And it's it's interesting how you
saying, you know, the IC's and Microsoft
and and and the partners and behind that
is obviously people, right? and and what
we're seeing is that traditional
partners, you know, the approach from
other partners in the BC space to find,
you know, experienced talent, but with
programs like the BC talent where we're
focusing on building kind of the next
generation of talent,
what skill sets do you think are needed
in the channel to meet the AI transition
over the next few years?
>> Okay, so first we have a big upskilling
problem. um just across the industry
just so you know uh every industry is
now saying we want AI people. The number
of people in the world who are AI
people, okay, AI people, AI engineers,
AI researchers, AI engineers, machine
learning people is like that bubble is
big. It's this big. And most normal
companies are never going to be able to
hire these people because there are not
enough. There's just not. So what we
have to do is grow that capability in
others. We have to go and aggressively
find people who are experts in a problem
space, skill them up on AI and drag them
into the tech community. We've done this
before, right? We we went through this.
Um we turned lots of accountants and
finance people into BC consultants.
We're going to have to do that again.
It's time to, you know, get out that
lasso and start corelling people. um in
we're having a moment where a lot of
people, you know, every day there's some
report coming out that says 100% of
white collar jobs will disappear next
year. And we're like, I don't know about
you, but we've never been so busy in our
lives. So, I don't know quite where
they're getting their information from.
Um but one of the things we have to do
is kind of reduce that fear by saying if
you are worried that your job will
disappear next year, dear accountant,
dear um tax prep person, dear financial
analyst, like whatever the job is that's
supposed to disappear next year, let's
get you skilled up on AI. Let's actually
teach you this is generative AI. Here's
how it works for your field. What does
your data set, a sample data set look
like for a tax accountant? Let's use AI
to reason over that and see where it's
useful, where it's not useful. Because
probably the most important thing they
can be doing right now is creating their
own workflow or here's a standard
workflow. AI is good for step one, step
three, and step 407. And here's a set of
prompt libraries that I use to do those
parts. If people can do that, they're
now called what is in my jurisdiction
called an AI power user. And once we
build up a huge community of AI power
users in each of these industries, then
we've got a whole bunch of people who
are ready to go and tackle the next
generation set of problems that
customers they may have today, they're
definitely going to have in the future.
But we've got a big upscaling problem
ahead of us. And we have to do it in a
way that feels structured to people. So
it's not, hey, go figure out AI on your
own, which is what we're saying right
now. We're saying, go figure out AI on
your own. Figure out how to do it in
your job. So we need a lot more
structure around it and we need people
who are willing to raise their hands and
sign up to go and do this. So the most
important thing all of you should be
doing is going to the BC talent page and
clicking on learn more because we really
want more people to come and join the BC
community because we want you to come
and first have a role in the AI verse.
Make my job easier folks because the
number of people reach out to me saying
we're looking for AI people. I have five
partners right now in my inbox saying we
need to hire AI people. bring us some AI
people. I'm saying my friends, I do not
grow them on trees, okay? I'm trying to
steal from your various communities and
grow them ourselves in a lab. But what
we need you to do is go to the BC talent
page, learn more, and come and join us.